David Freeman is eight years late for dinner, and his family wants to
know why. But David's got an absolutely fantastic excuse.
Flight of the Navigator is a family, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Randal Kleiser.
12-year-old David is accidentally knocked out in the forest near his
home, but when he awakens eight years have passed.
His family is overjoyed to have him back, but is just as
perplexed as he is that he hasn't aged.
When a NASA scientist discovers a UFO nearby, David gets the chance
to unravel the mystery and recover the life he lost.
David Scott Freeman, played by Joey Cramer.
Max (voice), played by Paul Reubens.
Helen Freeman, played by Veronica Cartwright.
Bill Freeman, played by Cliff DeYoung.
Carolyn McAdams, played by Sarah Jessica Parker.
Jeff (16 years), played by Matt Adler.
Flight of the Navigator is a 1986 American science-fiction adventure
film directed by Randal Kleiser and written by Mark H.
Baker, Michael Burton, and Phil Joanou.
It stars Joey Cramer as David Freeman, a 12-year-old boy abducted by an alien spaceship who,
as an unfortunate side-effect, is transported eight years into the future.
It features an early film appearance by Sarah Jessica Parker as Carolyn
McAdams, a key character in the future whom David befriends.
The film's producers initially sent the project to Walt Disney Pictures in 1984, but the studio was unable to approve it, and it
was sent to Producers Sales Organization, which made a deal with Disney to distribute it in the United States.
It was partially shot in Fort Lauderdale, Florida, and Norway, being
a co-production with Norwegian company Viking Film.
The film is notable for being one of the first Hollywood films to use
extensive computer-generated imagery (CGI) effects.
Specifically, it was the first use of image-based lighting and
an early use of morphing in a motion picture.
It is also known to be one of the first Hollywood productions to feature an entirely electronic music film
score, composed using a Synclavier, one of the first digital multitrack recorders and samplers.
The film has since developed a cult following among
science-fiction and Disney fans.
The latest plans for a reboot were announced in 2021.
The film explores themes of florida, farewell, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), flying saucer, nasa.
The tone is thought_provoking.